#### Contact

+917799170576 (Mobile) baruahsaswat@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/saswat-baruah-06b52419 (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Linux

С

Python

### Languages

**English** 

Hindi

Bengali

#### Certifications

Computer Networking Machine Learning

# Saswat Baruah

Senior Software Engineer

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

## Summary

Software Developer well versed in Linux, TCP/IP, HTTP, Network Security(TLS, OpenSSL), IPv6, SQL(Postgresql), NOSQL(Cassandra), caching and distributed message queues.

Experienced in Golang, C and C++ . Proficient in Multithreading and distributed systems.

Comfortable with Kubernetes, Docker and Google Cloud Platform for deployment, Git and SVN for versioning.

# Experience

### Startup

Senior Software Engineer May 2019 - Present (1 year 3 months) Bengaluru Area, India

- o Designed, developed and deployed multiple microservices
- o Worked extensively on services that communicate with Redis and Postgres
- o Extensively used HTTP(synchronous) and NATS(message queue for asynchronous communication).
- o Used json, protobuf and cbor for messaging

#### Polycom

5 years 11 months

Senior Software Developer May 2017 - May 2019 (2 years 1 month)

Hyderabad Area, India

Wi-Fi support for Linux phones

- o End to end design and development for supporting Wi-Fi connections
- o Development of the middle layer to interact with the driver/kernel
- o Implement scanning for available networks/access points and parsing of results using ioctl and netlink
- o Implement connection to open and secured networks using wpa\_supplicant

Network Security Features and Vulnerabilities

- o Worked on various security related features and vulnerabilities
- o Worked on TLS connection framework for server and client using OpenSSL

Redesign the framework for TCP connections

- o Redesigned the TCP connection framework (for both server and client) to allow alternate stack
- o Refactored using the Façade and Factory design patterns to allow alternate connection mechanisms
- o Worked on multithreaded processing of incoming connections using the Linux network stack

## Software Developer

June 2014 - May 2017 (3 years)

Hyderabad Area, India

DHCPv6 support for Linux phones

- o DHCPv6 is what automates the assignment of IP addresses for devices in IPv6 networks
- o Integrated ISC dhclient to make DHCPv6 function for devices
- o Worked on the state machine to implement duplicate address detection

Design and implementation of AOC

- o Advice of Charge alerts user about the incurred charges at the beginning, during and end of a call
- o Designed using MVC framework to show alerts on UI
- o Worked on SDP (SIP message body) processing and handling of AOC XML
- o Used RapidXml to parse XML body

#### Intern

July 2013 - June 2014 (1 year)

Silver Arc Solutions (India) Pvt. Ltd.

Intern

May 2012 - July 2012 (3 months)

Bhaskaracharya Institute of Space Applications and Geoinformatics Intern

May 2011 - July 2011 (3 months)

Gandhinagar, Gujarat

# Education

BITS Pilani

Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.), Computer Science · (2009 - 2014)

# Activity

07/06/2020, Saswat Baruah added candidate to Senior Software Engineer